<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Shawn&#39;s Docs</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Shawn&#39;s Docs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1. Corpora, Language Models, Smoothing</title>
      <link>/Courses/Natural-Language-Computing/1.-Corpora-Language-Models-Smoothing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/Courses/Natural-Language-Computing/1.-Corpora-Language-Models-Smoothing/</guid>
      <description>What are we counting? Tokens and types. Instances of words and kinds of words.
Corpora: A body of language data. Most useful when occurring naturally. Be aware of bias.
Vocabulary: Set of unique Words
Size of corpus: Total number of words
Word Order Matters! Should consider past words, but not ALL past words. \(P(car|the\:old) = 0\) may never appear in the corpus, but \(P(old|the) &amp;gt; 0\) and \(P(car|old) &amp;gt; 0\) could be true, \(\therefore P(the\:old\:car) &amp;gt; 0\).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1. Distributed Systems Examples</title>
      <link>/Courses/Distributed-Systems/1.-Distributed-Systems-Examples/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/Courses/Distributed-Systems/1.-Distributed-Systems-Examples/</guid>
      <description>Massively Scalable Key-Value Stores What are key-value stores? Container for key-value pairs (databases) Distributed, multi-component Non-relational Simpler query semantics for increased scalability, speed, availability, and flexibility Why needed?
Big data. Huge amount of internet users, stored data, frequent updates, fast retrievals. Good for failure detection, failure recovery, replication, memory store, versioning.
Horizontal scalability: user growth, more nodes Performance: single-record read and write operations Flexibility: adapt to changing data definitions Reliability: provides failure recovery (failure is the norm), thousands of components at play Availability and geo-distribution: Users are worldwide, data can be accessed worldwide Main operations: PUT, GET, and DELETE.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1. Review of Linear Algebra</title>
      <link>/Courses/Optimization-in-Machine-Learning/1.-Review-of-Linear-Algebra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/Courses/Optimization-in-Machine-Learning/1.-Review-of-Linear-Algebra/</guid>
      <description>Vectors and Matrices \[a = \begin{bmatrix} 1\\ 2\\ 3\\ \end{bmatrix} \in \R^3, A^{m \times n} = \begin{bmatrix}a_{11} &amp;amp; a_{12} &amp;amp; \cdots &amp;amp; a_{1n}\\a_{21} &amp;amp; a_{22} &amp;amp; \cdots &amp;amp; a_{2n}\\\vdots &amp;amp; \vdots &amp;amp; \ddots &amp;amp; \vdots \\a_{m1} &amp;amp; a_{m2} &amp;amp; \cdots &amp;amp; a_{mn}\end{bmatrix}\] Matrix Operations and Properties Addition The sum of two matrices \(A \in \R^{m \times n}, B \in \R^{m \times n}\) is defined as the element-wise sum, i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2. Optimization</title>
      <link>/Courses/Optimization-in-Machine-Learning/2.-Optimization/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/Courses/Optimization-in-Machine-Learning/2.-Optimization/</guid>
      <description>General Optimization \(\underset{x}{\text{minimize}}\: f(x)\) \(\text{subject to} \quad c_i(x) = 0, i \in \mathcal{E}\) ​ \(c_i(x) \geq 0, i \in \mathcal{J}\)
for Variables \(x\), Objective Function \(f(x)\) that satisfies \(f: \mathbb{R}^n \rightarrow \mathbb{R}\), Constraints \(\mathcal{E}, \mathcal{J}\) Here&amp;rsquo;s a quick example.
Notice we don&amp;rsquo;t use strictly greater than. Why? In a continuous domain it is not well-defined. There is no solution to the following optimization as you can get infinitely close to 1, but there is always some \(\delta\) that can be subtracted to get you even closer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2. Time</title>
      <link>/Courses/Distributed-Systems/2.-Time/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/Courses/Distributed-Systems/2.-Time/</guid>
      <description>hello</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cycling</title>
      <link>/Triathlon/cycle/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/Triathlon/cycle/</guid>
      <description>General Cycling Tips 😑</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Positioning</title>
      <link>/BJJGrappling/Positioning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/BJJGrappling/Positioning/</guid>
      <description> Side Control one arm wedged under head, twist that head same hand grabbing lats other hand connected/on stomach/elbow on hip tippy toe on feet and knees for pressure keep back relatively flat shoulders wide and pressing Closed Guard ankles crossed want high closed guard when breaking posture use primarily hips and knees to break posture use hand to control/swipe wrists use hand for necktie </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running</title>
      <link>/Triathlon/run/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/Triathlon/run/</guid>
      <description>General Running Tips 😑</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Submissions</title>
      <link>/BJJGrappling/Submissions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/BJJGrappling/Submissions/</guid>
      <description> Triangle From Closed Guard Punch arm in Hip up, get ankles crossed Grab ankle, kick off hip and pivot to the side Relock legs Swing opponent arm to the other side Hip up, pull head, squeeze 😴 From Mount Americana (from side control) Take arm out from under head Pin opponent&amp;rsquo;s hand to mat with that arm, use head and shoulders for leverage Bring elbow to neck Get other arm under and connect wrists Pull tight towards body and tilt their elbow up, using the wrists as the turning point (keep wrists on mat) </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sweeps</title>
      <link>/BJJGrappling/Sweeps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/BJJGrappling/Sweeps/</guid>
      <description>Closed Guard to Mount Hip Bump (optional) Break posture, begin as they regain posture
Elbow up, arm up
Keep necktie, or switch to cross shoulder
hip the shit out of them, TORQUE</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Swimming</title>
      <link>/Triathlon/swim/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/Triathlon/swim/</guid>
      <description>General Swimming Tips 🐬 Keep Body Horizontal Head Looking Straight Down Enter Stroke Extended, Angle Fingers Flat on the Surface Turn Body to Breathe High Elbow 4 Quick Kicks Per Stroke Keep Non-Pulling Arm Straight in Water until Other Arm almost Enters Workouts Here are some typical workout plans to get started:
Warm up Rest Time 150m easy, 50m any @ 2:45 ~ 3:00 pace 30s Fill in Thursday Main Rest Time 300 easys Fill in Thursday Swimming Forms Freestyle (Frontcrawl) Fast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Takedowns</title>
      <link>/BJJGrappling/Takedowns/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/BJJGrappling/Takedowns/</guid>
      <description> Double Leg Takedown Tips If collartied, let go and pop their arms with C clamps real fast:
pop arms with C clamp real fast Get knee between their legs stay upright, head close to hip Wrap arm around thighs/knees and drive forward Keep other leg around 45 degrees and use it as a driving anchor If they don&amp;rsquo;t fall from the initial drive:
Stand up and use that leg to drive diagonally a bit, throwing their legs to the other direction, OR Do the weird pigeon/S mount ankle trip </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>White</title>
      <link>/Judo/White/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/Judo/White/</guid>
      <description> Break Fall chin tucked hips low, try not to roll 45 degree arms, never use elbows huge S L A P P Hip Throw (Ogoshi) Set opponent slightly off balance Grab behind with one arm Also reposition with feet to get MAX hip torque Scarf Hold (Kesa Gatame) OTHER arm around neck (compared to side control) other arm constraint opponent wrist and shoulder legs splayed, good to shuffle so doesn&amp;rsquo;t get trapped head close down and tight to opponent </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
